A Guide to the Capital Area Agency on Aging records, 1979-1998
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
Capital Area Agency on Aging records, 1979-1998
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 361
2.9 linear feet.
Capital Area Agency on Aging
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Capital Area Agency on Aging in 2006.
Historical Information
The Capital Area Agency on Aging was established in 1973. It is a private nonprofit organization dedicated to serving seniors in Richmond, Virginia and its surrounding counties, and it is part of a national network of Area Agencies on Aging. The agency seeks to empower area seniors to optimize their quality of life and maintain their independence as long as they wish. They provide planning assistance to seniors and caregivers and help them identify the public and private service providers that can best meet their needs. Other programs run by the agency provide guidance on care management, assistance finding employment and volunteer opportunities for seniors, caregiver support, insurance counseling, information about elder rights, and meal services. In 2000, the Capital Area Agency on Aging changed its name to Senior Connection, Capital Area Agency on Aging.
Scope and Content
This collection contains materials created by the Capital Area Agency on Aging that document the agency’s operations, programs, and outreach activities. The majority of the collection consists of correspondence, minutes, and other documents generated by the agency’s committees. Also included are records concerning various service programs as well as reference materials.
Arrangement
Collection is divided into three series: Committee Files, 1978-1999; Community Engagement and Program Materials, 1974-1998; and Reference Materials, 1982-2006. Within series, files are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Contents List
- Series 1: Committee Files, 1978-1999
  - Executive Committee - Board of Directors, 1988-1998 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Executive Committee - Correspondence, 1990-1998 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Executive Committee - Minutes, 1983-1998 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Executive Committee - Reference Materials, Chamber of Commerce, 1987-1999, undated (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Finance Committee - Correspondence, 1980-1997 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Finance Committee - Financial Documents, Reference Materials, and Notes, 1988-1998, undated (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Finance Committee - Financial Statements and Audits, 1978-1997 (Box-folder 1:7-2:1)
  - Finance Committee - Fiscal Year Plans, 1978-1997 (Box-folder 2:2-2:4)
  - Finance Committee - Investment Information and Policies, 1997-1998, undated (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Finance Committee - Minutes, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Grant Review and Evaluation Committee - Correspondence and Grant Materials, 1982-1990, 1998 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Grant Review and Evaluation Committee - Minutes, 1984-1993 (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Grant Review and Evaluation Committee - Report on In-Home Services, 1983 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Human Resources Committee - Benefits Materials, 1986, 1994-1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Human Resources Committee - Compensation Materials, Organization Charts, and Position Descriptions, 1991-1993, undated (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Human Resources Committee - Correspondence, 1981, 1990-1998 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Human Resources Committee - Minutes, 1986-1998 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Human Resources Committee - Report of Internal Evaluation, 1981 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Long Range Planning Committee - Correspondence, 1991, 1996 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Long Range Planning Committee - Minutes, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Long Range Planning Committee - Strategic Plan Materials, 1994-1998 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Long Range Planning Committee - Reference Materials, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Nominating Committee - Correspondence, 1993-1998 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - Nominating Committee - Member Lists, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 3:12)
  - Nominating Committee - Minutes, 1990-1998 (Box-folder 3:13)
  - Nominating Committee - Nominations Lists, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 3:14)
  - Nominating Committee - Reference Materials, 1985, 1995, undated (Box-folder 3:15)
  - Public Policy Committee - Correspondence, 1981, 1988-1997 (Box-folder 3:16)
  - Public Policy Committee - Legislative and Lobbying Materials, 1981-1998, undated (Box-folder 3:17)
  - Public Policy Committee - Minutes, 1983, 1989-1997 (Box-folder 3:18)
  - Public Policy Committee - Reference Materials, 1981-1997, undated (Box-folder 3:19)
- Series 2: Community Engagement and Program Materials, 1974-1998
  - Better Business Bureau, 1996, undated (Box-folder 3:20)
  - Business Cards - Harris Spindle, undated (Box-folder 3:21)
  - CAAA Annual Meetings, 1988-1994, undated (Box-folder 3:22)
  - Church Presentations 1974, 1981-1997, undated (Box-folder 4:1)
  - Diversity Workshops, 1994-1997, undated (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Legal Service Information - AARP Files, 1992, 1994 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Legal Service Information - Pro-Bono Legal Aid, 1986-1996, undated (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Legal Service Information - Virginia State Bar, 1987-1995, undated (Box-folder 4:5)
  - National Aging Program Information System, 1994-1998, undated (Box-folder 4:6-5:1)
  - Richmond Long-Term Care Committee - Companion and Guardian Programs, 1988-1992, undated (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Richmond Long-Term Care Committee - Correspondence, 1988-1993, undated (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Richmond Long-Term Care Committee - Minutes, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Richmond Long-Term Care Committee - Reference Materials, 1982, 1988 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - Southern Gerontological Society Membership Directory, 1993 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - Triad - Advisory Committee Minutes, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - Triad - Clippings and Publications, 1980-1998, undated (Box-folder 5:8)
  - Triad - Correspondence, 1996-1998, undated (Box-folder 5:9)
  - Triad - Program Materials and Survey, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 5:10)
  - Virginia Association on Aging, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 5:11)
  - Virginia Coalition for the Aging, 1998 (Box-folder 5:12)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Presentations, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 5:13)
  - Virginia Energy and Aging Consortium - Correspondence, 1987-1988, 1995 (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Virginia Energy and Aging Consortium - Minutes, 1988, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 5:15)
  - Virginia Energy and Aging Consortium - Reference Materials, 1994-1998, undated (Box-folder 5:16)
  - Virginia Energy and Aging Consortium - Member Lists, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 5:17)
  - Virginia Housing Coalition - Bylaws, 1994 (Box-folder 5:18)
  - Virginia Housing Coalition - Correspondence, 1988-1996, undated (Box-folder 5:19)
  - Virginia Housing Coalition - Member Lists, 1996 (Box-folder 5:20)
  - Virginia Housing Coalition - Reference Materials, 1993-1997, undated (Box-folder 5:21)
  - Volunteer Programs for Seniors, 1990-1998, undated (Box-folder 6:1)
  - White House Conference on Aging, 1981, 1995 (Box-folder 6:2)
- Series 3: Reference Materials, 1982-2006
  - Age Care Sourcebook, 1987 (Box-folder 6:3)
  - Aging, 1970, 1984-1997, undated (Box-folder 6:4)
  - Comprehensive Services Act, 1997 (Box-folder 6:5)
  - Ethics and Euthanasia, 1988-1997, undated (Box-folder 6:6)
  - The Healing Zone Health Update, 2006 (Box-folder 7:1)
  - Hunger Studies, 1985, 1992-1998, undated (Box-folder 7:2)
  - Management and Employee Relations 1979-1994, undated (Box-folder 7:3)
  - Patient Self-Determination Act, 1991-1997, undated (Box-folder 7:4)
  - Sexuality and Aging Study, 1987 (Box-folder 7:5)
  - Speech Writing, 1982, 1988-1990, undated (Box-folder 7:6)
  - Viaticus, 1996 (Box-folder 7:7)
  - Virginia's Area Agencies on Aging: Making a Difference - Best Practices, 2005 (Box-folder 7:8)